<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-20T18:42:07+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">codzilla</title><subtitle>A developer's journey through the jungles of code.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tips for a fulfilling college life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/01/31/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips for a fulfilling college life" /><published>2018-01-31T05:28:20+05:30</published><updated>2018-01-31T05:28:20+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/01/31/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/01/31/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;After a gruelling two years of slogging for JEE, the extent of which I now truly appreciate with an improved third-person-clarity, I got admitted into IIT Roorkee. The final four years of my school days passed away disgustingly quick, and I do look back with some regret. Although, it seems I didn’t really learn from that experience. Maybe another blog post is in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve often wondered what I felt like during that period of result declaration and eventual college admittance. I believe I was largely indifferent to which IIT I went to as long as it wasn’t a very new one. Later on it became evident to me that this was an anomaly; a lot of my peers tended to have strong opinions regarding their preferences at that time. To my mind, all IITs were good enough and getting into one was the thing to care about. This opinion has changed now, and I do acknowledge the differences in IITs, perhaps not in terms of placement stats as many lean towards as comparison metrics, but more in terms of culture, or to put it simply, how well could a student spend a regular day. To sum up, I was satisfied with getting into IIT Roorkee, largely because I had no reason to not be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As declared earlier, I won’t dive into details of my individual achievements or regrets during my college life. There might be things that I’m proud about. There might be things I deeply regret. There might be things that I’m indifferent to but might be proud about or regret in future. Nevertheless, I shall refrain from making this post personal. I’m afraid doing so might perhaps restrict the audience that I’m comfortable sharing it with, and that’s just a headache. Nobody likes a headache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are some tips, in order of whatever comes to my mind, of what I believe &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; constitute a fulfilling college experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-kind-to-others&quot;&gt;Be kind to others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most cliched, overused and downright boring thing to read, hear and especially say, but really important for your happiness and others around you. I would like to reaffirm here that these tips should not be considered a derivation from my life, I do not claim the moral authority to be preachy, nor do I claim to be the beacon of kindness or similar virtues. Instead, consider this a detached todo list that I’m laying down, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be kind to others. Doesn’t this fit more in the general set of being-a-good-person-advices instead of a list specifically for college? Maybe it does, but it is quite significant here. College can be a cruel place. For a majority of students, it is the gateway exposure to independence, with their entire previous life having been spent at home. Earlier they were persistently surrounded by family that consumed a major portion of their time. Now they have a lot of things going on in their lives, and a lot of time to ponder over them in isolation. It is not uncommon for people to spiral into negativity, to develop insecurities, jealousy and even animosity. The reasons can be complex and personal. One thing that you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do is try to be socially empathetic. You never know what someone might be insecure about. A thoughtless word or a senseless action, despite you not intending to cause anyone harm, might hurt someone. At the same time, try to be lenient and forgiving. Do remember that often a person’s behaviour tends to be a product of circumstances, and does not define who he/she really is. Which brings me to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-judgement-will-often-be-wrong&quot;&gt;Your judgement will often be wrong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impression is the last impression. Or is it? Diverging a bit from the promise of being impersonal earlier, I’ll just say that I can personally vouch that it isn’t. I’ve known people who I badly misjudged. I’ve probably been misjudged too. Be wary of negativity, but try not to push people away because you developed an incorrect notion about them. Don’t be entirely driven by emotions while evaluating people, try to maintain some rationality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-be-a-sycophant&quot;&gt;Don’t be a sycophant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the one thing thing I’ve delivered the most impassioned speeches(rants) on to friends, especially so in final year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-what-matters-to-you-and-do-it&quot;&gt;Find what matters to you and do it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-neglect-what-youre-good-at&quot;&gt;Don’t neglect what you’re good at&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-lose-a-grip-over-reality&quot;&gt;Don’t lose a grip over reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-care-of-yourself&quot;&gt;Take care of yourself&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Nikhil Kaushik</name></author><summary type="html">After a gruelling two years of slogging for JEE, the extent of which I now truly appreciate with an improved third-person-clarity, I got admitted into IIT Roorkee. The final four years of my school days passed away disgustingly quick, and I do look back with some regret. Although, it seems I didn’t really learn from that experience. Maybe another blog post is in order.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/11/28/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2017-11-28T05:28:20+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-28T05:28:20+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/11/28/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2017/11/28/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikhil Kaushik</name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>